So our layout's looking pretty good, but
그래서 우리의 레이아웃은 보기에는 아름다우나
when I press these buttons, nothing's really happening.
이 버튼들을 눌렀을 때 아무 일도 일어나지 않아요
What you're going to need to do is associate the XML and the Java so
해야할 일은 해당 XML과 자바를 연결지어
that when you press a button some sort of event happens in the Java code.
버튼을 눌렀을 때 어떤 종류의 일이든 자바코드에서 일어나도록 하는 겁니다
Now you've done this already with the Just Java app, so
이제 Just Java 앱으로 여러분은 그걸 이미 해보셨고
you're going to do some similar steps now.
이제 동일한 절차 몇 가지를 해볼 겁니다
Okay, so the first thing you're going to do is copy and paste over
좋습니다, 처음 할 일로서 복사해 붙여넣을 것은
the displayForTeamA method, which I've provided in the instructor notes.
displayForTeamA 메서드인데 강의 노트에 제공해 드렸습니다
I'll show you how to do that right now.
지금 바로 방법을 보여드리죠
Okay, so here I am in my XML code, but
여기 제가 작성한 XML 코드에 들어와 있지만
we actually want to be in the Java code for this.
이에 대한 자바 코드 환경에 있기를 바라는 겁니다
Now, you might have Main activity.java opened in another tab, but if not,
이제 Main activity.java를 별도의 탭으로 열었을 텐데, 아직 안 했다면
go ahead and head up to the Java folder, and then click on the first of the two,
자바 폴더로 가서 두 개 중에 첫 번째를 클릭하시면
Now, this is the main activity class and
이제 이것이 메인 액티비티 클래스이며
it contains these code chunks called methods.
여기는 메서드라고 부르는 이 코드 뭉치들을 포함하고 있어요
What I want you to do is paste it inside of the main activity class, but
여러분이 하실 일은 그걸 메인 액티비티 클래스 안에 붙여넣는 것인데
not inside of any of the other methods.
다른 메서드들 안에는 붙여넣지 마세요
So let's look at where the main activity class starts.
메인 액티비티 클래스가 시작하는 장소를 살펴 봅시다
It begins up here, and
여기에서 시작하고 있는데
I'll scroll down a little more slowly, and it ends down here.
좀 더 천천히 아래로 내리면 여기에서 끝나는군요
Right before the last curly brace, so not within this method, but
마지막 중괄호 바로 직전에
I'm on a Mac, if you're on a Windows, you can use Control+V.
저는 매킨토시 환경인데, 윈도우를 쓴다면 콘트롤+V키를 사용할 수 있어요
Now I'm seeing a lot of red, and
이제 빨간 글씨가 많이 보이는데
that's actually because I don't have auto-import turned on on this computer.
이 컴퓨터에는 자동 불러오기 기능이 켜져 있지 않기 때문이에요
So I'm going to do that.
고로 그걸 해볼 겁니다
If you're also seeing red here,
여러분 역시 빨간 글자가 여기에 보인다면
that means that you're probably having the same problem.
아마도 같은 문제가 있다는 뜻입니다
Catherine showed how to do it in lesson two and I've provided a link in
캐서린이 2강에서 하는 법을 보여드렸고 제가 링크를 제공해드렸는데
the instructor notes if you need to watch that video again.
그 영상을 다시 시청할 필요가 있으면 강의 노트에 있습니다
Okay, much better.
좋습니다, 훨씬 낫군요
I've still got a little bit of red.
여전히 빨간 글자가 좀 보이네요
Let's resolve that right now.
지금 당장 그 문제를 해결해 봅시다
Okay, so I've done step one.
좋아요, 1단계를 완료했습니다
The next thing that you need to do is change the ID
다음에 하실 일은 ID를 변경하는 것인데
of the score text view to be team_a_score.
스코어 텍스트뷰의 ID를 team_a_score로 바꾸는 겁니다
I'll also show you how to do that right now.
역시, 지금 당장 하는 법을 보여드릴 겁니다
For this one, I'm actually going to go over to the activity main XML, and
이것에 대해서, 액티비티 메인 XML로 갈 것인데
now we're in our XML and I'm going to look for
이제 XML에 들어와 있으며 제가 찾을 것은
the TextView that displays the score.
해당 스코어를 화면에 출력하는 텍스트뷰입니다
Here are my two TextViews, and it's this TextView here that has the text zero,
여기에 두 개의 텍스트뷰가 있는데 텍스트 0을 가진 텍스트뷰가 이것이며
which is displaying the score.
해당 스코어를 보여주고 있네요
I'm going to set the ID for that, I'll just go ahead and
이제 그에 대한 ID를 설정할 것인데 계속하여
start by typing ID, and I do want an ID.
ID를 기입하는 것부터 시작할 것이며 정말로 ID가 필요합니다
Okay and now it's giving me different options, but
좋아요, 지금 여러 다른 방안을 제시하지만
i'm going to use the at symbol plus id.
저는 @symbol+id를 이용할 겁니다
Which if you remember it was team_ a_score.
즉, 기억하신다면 id는 team_ a_score였습니다
Okay cool. All right and
좋습니다
it should be typed like that exactly.
정확히 그렇게 입력되어야 합니다
matches exactly with this word right here, team_a_score.
그건 바로 여기 team_a_score라는 단어와 정확히 일치합니다
And once you do this, this should change from a unhealthy red color,
일단 이걸 하시면, 이건 문제가 있어 보이는 빨간 색에서
to a healthy purple color, and your display method is going to work for you.
상쾌한 보라색으로 바뀔 것이며 화면 표시 메서드도 여러분 원하는대로 작동할 겁니다
If you want to test it out,
시험해 보길 원하시면
you can actually go up in your Java code to the onCreate method.
여러분의 자바 코드에서 위로 올라가 onCreate 메서드로 가시면 됩니다
Catherine had mentioned that onCreate occurs right when your app starts up.
캐서린은 onCreate가 여러분 앱이 시작할 때 즉시 일어난다고 언급했습니다
So I can actually add the code here, displayForTeam A,
고로 제가 여기에 해당 코드 즉, displayForTeam A를 추가할 수 있어요
and give it whatever your favorite number is, mine happens to be eight, and
그리고 여러분이 선호하는 아무 숫자나 넣을 수 있는데 저는 8로 택했습니다
I should be able to see that immediately the score will get updated to eight.
즉시, 해당 스코어가 8로 갱신되는 걸 볼 수 있을 겁니다
So I'm going to go ahead and run this, and see if that is true.
고로 이어서 이를 실행하여 그게 참인지 확인할 겁니다
Okay, so here's my app, and it's very small, but
좋아요, 이게 제 앱인데 아주 작지만
you should be able to see that this is 8 and not 0.
이게 0이 아니라 8이라는 걸 보실 수 있을 겁니다
So I did the first two steps correctly, and you should test, too,
그래서 저는 처음 두 단계를 정확히 수행했으니 여러분도 시험해 보셔서
to make sure that you did those first two steps correctly.
처음 두 단계를 정확히 수행했는지 꼭 확인해 보세요
In the next lesson, you're actually going to learn about how this code
다음 강의에서는 이 코드가 어떻게 작동하는지 배워볼 예정입니다
Okay. Now, for the fun part.
좋습니다, 지금은 재미있는 부분을 보기만 하세요
So, I'm not going to give you instructions about how to do this, but
이를 실행하는 방법에 대해 지시사항을 드리지 않겠지만
I will link you to some videos where Catherine did very similar things.
캐서린이 매우 흡사한 것을 시연하는 영상을 알려드리겠습니다
I want you to give the following behavior: when the plus 3 points is
다음 반응을 여러분이 보여주기를 바랍니다: + 3 points를 클릭하면
clicked it should show three.
3이 나올 겁니다
When plus 2 points is clicked, it should show two.
+2 points를 클릭할 때 2가 나타날 겁니다
When free throw is clicked, it should show one.
'free throw'를 클릭할 때 1이 나타날 겁니다
Here I'll show you on my phone.
여기 제 전화에서 보여드리겠습니다
Okay, so here is what I mean.
좋습니다, 이게 제가 의도한 내용입니다
I have my app I click the plus 3 points, 3 is shown, I click plus 2 points,
제 앱에서 +3 points를 누르면 3이 나오고 +2 points를 누르면
2 is shown, and I click free-throw and one is shown.
2가 나오며 'free-throw'를 누르면 1이 나타납니다
Now when I click plus 2 points again it just shows two.
이제 +2 points를 다시 클릭할 때 바로 2가 나옵니다
Its not adding anything yet.
아직 아무 것도 추가하지 않습니다
Now I know this isn't the final functionality that I was looking for,
이제 이게 제가 바랐던 최종 기능이 아니라는 걸 알지만
but it's a good intermediate state.
중도적인 상태로는 적당합니다
It's important to take intermediate goals to get you closer to
최종 목표에 다가가기 위해 중간 목표를 택하는 게
the final goal.
중요합니다
You do something small like you already know how to do, check,
여러분이 이미 할 줄 아는 자그마한 것을 해보고 확인하여
make sure it works and then modify it to get what you need.
제대로 작동하는지 검토하고 필요한 것을 얻기 위해 수정하세요
So, we'll start with this, and when you're done go ahead and check this box.
고로, 이것으로 시작할 것이고 완료하면 이 공란을 체크하세요